Tēlemachos Alaveras Papers and Nea Poreia Archives, 1989-2010: Finding Aid C1408
Manuscripts Division
Tēlemachos Alaveras Papers and Nea Poreia Archives
1889-2010
Manuscripts Division
Alaveras, Tēlemachos
C1408
97 boxes
2 items
39.3 linear feet
Consists of personal papers of Tēlemachos Alaveras, a prolific Modern Greek writer and editor of the literary magazine Nea Poreia for more than fifty years. He was also the president of the Literary Society of Thessalonikē and member of boards of many other organizations. Included also are the archives of Nea Poreia, as well as the personal papers of Alaveras's father, Chrēstos Alaveras.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
For preservation reasons, original analog and digital media may not be read or played back in the reading room. Users may visually inspect physical media but may not remove it from its enclosure. All analog audiovisual media must be digitized to preservation-quality standards prior to use. Audiovisual digitization requests are processed by an approved third-party vendor. Please note, the transfer time required can be as little as several weeks to as long as several months and there may be financial costs associated with the process. Requests should be directed through the Ask Us Form.
Scope and Contents
The collection comprises ninety-seven boxes of autograph manuscripts and typescripts, correspondence, printed material, audio-visual material, and photographs pertaining to Tēlemachos Alaveras as a Greek writer and as an editor of the literary magazine Nea Poreia. The papers include personal correspondence with major Greek writers and poets, such as Rita Boumē Papa, Dinos Christianopoulos, Margarita Dalmatē, Nikos Dēmou, Giōrgos Iōannou, Timos Malanos, Michalēs Meraklēs, Takēs Papatsōnēs, Pantelēs Prevelakēs, Apostolos Sachinēs, Helenē Vakalo, Giōrgos Veēs, and Chrysanthē Zitsaia. Included also are Alaveras's first writings, notebooks, talks, book reviews, interviews, and awards; writings by other people; the archives of the magazine Nea Poreia; material of other Greek associations or organizations where Alaveras was a board member or president; and finally, personal papers of Chrēstos Alaveras, Tēlemachos Alaveras's father.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series:
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Program in Hellenic Studies with the support of the Stanley J. Seeger Hellenic Fund.
Appraisal
Nothing was removed from the collection.
Alaveras, Tēlemachos
Biographical / Historical
Tēlemachos Alaveras was born on September 30, 1926 in Plovdiv, Eastern Rumelia (now Bulgaria). The following year his family moved to Thessalonikē, a city they were destined never to leave. The writer appears in the literature with stories in magazines, and soon he asserts himself and becomes famous all over Greece. In 1952 he issued his first book, a series of stories drawn from the civil war in Greece, with the title Ta agrimia tou allou dasous. But the writer first appeared with the novel To horologi, second edition 1990, in the Greek literature. After that Alaveras published the books To miso tou phengariou (stories, 1960), second edition 1990; To sēmerino syngraphiko provlēma (essay, 1961); Hodostrōtēras, (novel, 1963), second edition 1973, third edition 1988. After a great break, Alaveras publishes the study Diēgēmatographoi tēs Thessalonikēs in 1970, and in 1971 the forerunning play in one act Hoi alloi. Apart from these his main study "Ta logotechnika periodika tēs Thessalonikēs (1880-1955)" ["The literary magazines of Thessalonikē (1880-1995)"] was published in stories to be continued in the early press. In 1976 Alaveras issued seven stories with the title Ap'aphormē (second edition 1978). In 1977 this book received the First State Prize for story-writings. In 1985 he issued the volume of stories with the title Gōnies kai opseis, second edition 1988, which received the Ouranē Prize by the Academy of Athens. In 1987 he published the prose "Archeion" Averkiou Sverkiadē," and in 1990 the book Se eutheia grammē. Taxidi stēn Polōnia. In 1991 this book received the National Chronicle-Witness Award. In 1990 he issued one volume with critical notes in books with the title Sēmeiōseis.
Alaveras was the editor of the literary magazine Nea Poreia from the day the magazine was issued (1955). He was also the president of the Literary Society of Thessalonikē. He was a member of boards of state organizations and literary competitions, theater, and film-competitions.
His works have been translated into German, Dutch, Italian, Bulgarian, Swedish, Serbian, and Polish. Tēlemachos Alaveras belongs to the post-war novelists of Thessalonikē and is one of the first writers who exploited the theme of the Greek Civil War period. Married to poet Roula Alavera and had two sons. He died on June 30, 2007.
Authors, Greek (Modern). -- 20th century -- Correspondence; Authors, Greek (Modern) -- 20th century -- Manuscripts.; Greek literature, Modern. -- 20th century; Greek poetry, Modern. -- 20th century; Poets -- Greek (Modern). -- 20th century -- Correspondence; Poets -- Greek (Modern) -- 20th century -- Manuscripts.; Correspondence -- 20th century; Manuscripts, Greek. -- 20th century; Notebooks. -- 20th century; photographs -- 19th century; photographs -- 20th century; Alavera, Roula; Boumē Papa, Rita (1906-1984); Christianopoulos, D̲inos; Dalmatê, Margarita.; Prevelakēs, Pantelēs (1909-1986)
- Series 1: Tēlemachos Alaveras Papers, 1889-2010; 47 boxes; 2 items
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of Tēlemachos Alaveras's autograph and typed manuscript drafts of his writings; correspondence with his friends, colleagues, and acquaintants; documents; writings by others; personal photographs or in connection with Nea Poreia; audio-visual material; and clippings of newspapers and literary magazines.
  Arrangement
  This series has been organized into ten subseries: A. Correspondence; B. Works by Alaveras; C. Talks, Questionnaires, TV Series, and Interviews; D. Conferences and Meetings; European Programs; E. Literary Competitions and Awards; F. Documents; G. Writings by Others; H. Photographs; I. Audio-Visual Material; Designs; and K. Printed Material.
  - Subseries 1A: Correspondence, 1924-2010; 14 boxes
    This subseries consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence with Tēlemachos Alaveras's close friends, colleagues, acquaintances, institutions, organizations, and foundations.
    This subseries has been arranged in a chronological order by last name of individual or institution.
    - A (General), 1956-1982; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Includes incoming correspondence from: Atzakas, Giannēs; Asprogerakas-Grivas, Kōnstantinos; Alexiou, Ellē; Anagnōstakēs, Manolēs; Andriōtēs, N. P. (Nikolaos P.); and Andrikopoulos, Giannēs.
    - Alaveras, Chrēstos, 1991-2002; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alaveras, Panagiōtēs, 1995-2001; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alavera, Stauroula (Roula), 1965-2000; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Alaveras, Tēlemachos, 1935-2007; 3 folders (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
      Includes incoming and outgoing correspondence with his father, Chrēstos Alaveras; his mother, Aikaterinē (Katina) Alavera and his brother Agēsilaos Alaveras, friends, colleagues, acquiantances, and relatives.
    - Alexiou, Christos D., 1974; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Anagnōstou, Giōrgos, 2004-2007; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Anastasiadēs, Savvas, 1945-1947; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Anatolia College, 1956-2004; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Angelakēs, Andreas, 1981-1987; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Anthemēs, Phoivos, 1955; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Antoniadēs, Vyrōn K., 1974-2005; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Antōniou, Chrēstos, 1980-1984; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Antōniou, Kreōn N., 1946-1952; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Aristoteleio Panepistēmio Thessalonikēs, 1964-2003; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Argyriadēs, Dēmētrēs and Euanthia, 1959-1969; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Argyriou, Alexandros, 1958-1980; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Asēmakopoulos, Kōstas, 1955-1978; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Aspiōtēs, Euangelos N., 1957-1969; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Athanasiadēs, Nikos, 1964; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Athanasiadēs, Tasos, 1961-2000; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Athanasopoulou, Maria, 2001; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Athanasoulēs, Kritōn, 1955-1978; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Aulōnitou, Lyntia [Katakalos, L.], 1955-1977; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Averōph-Iōannou, Tatiana (Pinakothēkē Averōph), 2005-2006; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bampiniōtēs, Geōrgios, 1999-2006; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bakirtzēs, Ch. (Charalampos), 1967-1995; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Belies, Herrikos, 1983-1988; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Binet, J., undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Boumē Papa, Rita, 1962; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - The British Council, 1986-1991; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - C (General), 1969-1974; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Includes incoming correspondence from: Chatzēanagnōstou, Takēs; Chourmouziadēs, G. D.; Chadzinikolau, Nikos; Chatzēdakēs, Petros; and Charalampous, Marios Marinos.
    - Caranfil, Andrew G., 1994-1995; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Centre international d'études poétiques, 1961-1981; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Charalampidēs, Kyriakos, 1975-1976; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Charēs, Petros, 1961-1998; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Chatzēpateras, Kōstas N., 1964-2002; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Chatzopoulou-Karavia, Leia, 1961-1975; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Chrēstou, Chrysanthos, 1971-1976; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Christianopoulos, Dinos, 1950-2006; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Chrysanthēs, Kypros, 1956-1995; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - D (General), 1952-1991; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Includes incoming correspondence from: Doulis, Thomas; Dēmaras, Kōnstantinos; Darakē, Pepē; Delopoulos, Kyriakos; Daphnēs, Kōstas; Dephner, Othōn M.; Dēmoules Stergios; Delēgiōrgē, Alexandra; Dēmētriadēs, Dēmētrēs; Taxiarchēs, Dinos; Diamantidēs, Antōnēs; and Dedousēs, V.
    - Dalakoura, Veronikē, 1999; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Dallas, Giannēs, 1956-1957; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Dalias, Chrēstos (see also Nea Poreia), 1956-1982; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Dalmatē, Margarita, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Daniēl, Giōrgos, 1980-1988; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Daousanēs, Athan. V., 1993-2007; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Degiannēs, Giannēs, undated; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Delios, Giōrgos, 1924-1975; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Delphēs, Phoivos, 1956-1962; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Dēmadēs, K. A., 1966-2000; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Dēmakēs, Mēnas, 1954-1977; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Demertzēs, Kōstas, 1960-1966; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Dēmos Thessalonikēs, 1955-2006; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Dēmou, Dēmētrios, 1973-1982; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Dēmou, Nikos, 1981-1982; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Dēmoula, Kikē, 1987-2006; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Depountēs, Iasōn, 1961-1991; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Đidić, Ljubiša, 1984; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Diethnēs Ekthesē Thessalonikēs [Thessalonikē International Fair], 1952-2004; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Includes incoming correspondence and autograph manuscript notes by Tēlemachos Alaveras.
    - Diktaios, Arēs, 1955-1956; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Dōssas, Gerasimos, 1955-1956; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Doxas, Angelos, 1954; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Doxas, Takēs, 1955-1963; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Ēpeirotikē Hestia [Dēmosthenēs Kokkinos], 1956-1988; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Epitheōrēsē Technēs, 1962; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Ethnikē Hetairia tōn Hellēnōn Logotechnōn, 1965-1997; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Ethnikē Vivliothēkē tēs Hellados, 1960-2006; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Ethniko Kentro Vivliou, 1997-2004; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Eustratiadēs, Aurēlios, 1964-1966; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Folklife and Ethnological Museum of Macedonia, 1989-1994; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - La Fondation Octavio Paz, 2001; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Friar, Kimon, 1973; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - G (General), 1956-2006; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Includes incoming correspondence from: Geranēs, Stelios; Geōrgiadēs Kyproleōn, A.A.; Galazē, Pitsa; Giakos, Dēmētrēs; Gonatas, E. Ch.; Grollios, K. Ch.; Giakos, Dēmētrēs; Grēgoriadēs, Nikos; and Giachetti, Mauro.
    - Galanakē-Vourlekē, Antigonē, 1963-1973; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Gálvez Garcia, Isabel, 2002-2005; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Gennadius Library, 2000-2004; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Geralēs, Giōrgos, 1991-1993; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Gialourakēs, Manōlēs, 1961-1968; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Giannopoulos, Alkiviadēs, 1956-1980; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Giannopoulos, Takēs, 1956-1981; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Ginopoulos, Vas., 1974-1975; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Giokarinē, Pēnelopē, 1956-1986; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Glezos, Petros, 1960-1985; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Goudelēs, Giannēs, 1963-1987; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Greek Orthodox Archdiocese of Australia [Archbishop Stylianos], 2004-2006; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Grēgoriadēs, Vasil. N. (Bookstore), 1956-1971; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Harrassowitz, Otto, 1966-1971; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Harvard College Library, 1969-1989; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Hellenic Authors' Society, 2003-2005; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Hellēnikē Periēgētikē Leschē, 1962-1964; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Hellēnikē Viomēchania Zacharēs A.E., 1977-1994; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Hellēnogalliko Kollegio "Delasal" [Greek-French College De La Salle], 1953-1995; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Hetairia Hellēnōn Logotechnōn, 1986; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Hetaireia Makedonikōn Spoudōn-Hidryma Meletōn Chersonēsou tou Haimou (Institute for Balkan Studies), 1958-1990; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Hetairia Logotechnōn Thessalonikēs, 1964-2010; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Hidryma Kōsta kai Helenēs Ouranē, 1979-2007; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Hidryma Kōstē Palama, 1993-2006; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Homilos Synergatōn kai Hypostēriktōn tōn "Morphōn" (Ho.S.Y.M), 1952; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Horizontes [Vayanos, Marios], 1971-1974; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Hypourgeio Politismou, Hellēnikē Dēmokratia (Ministry of Culture), 1972-1999; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Hypourgeio Politismou, Hellēnikē Dēmokratia (Ministry of Culture), 2000-2007; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Hypourgeion Proedrias Kyvernēseōs [Ministry of the Government], 1955-1986; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Ianos, 2002-2009; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Institouto Vivliou kai Anagnōsēs Kozanē (Institute of Book and Reading), 1997; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Institut français d'Athènes; Institut franc̜ais de Thessalonique, 1952-2001; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Iōannidēs, I. D., 1983-1993; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Iōannidēs, Kōstas, 1970-2007; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Iōannou, Giōrgos, 1955-1983; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Istituto Universitario Orientale, 1983-1995; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - K (General), 1959-2007; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Includes incoming correspondence from: Kassos, Vangelēs; Kostouros, Theodōros K.; Kasapidēs, Giōrgos; Kokkinēs, Spyros; Karydēs, Dēmētrēs; Kougioumtzēs, Mimēs; Karavias, Panos,Kazaglēs, Dionysēs; Kourēs, Nasos; Katakalos, Pierre; Karterēs, Giōrgos; Kournoutos, G.P.; Kaklamanakē, Roula; Kordomenidēs, Giōrgos
    - Kachtitsēs, Nikos, 1959-1960; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Includes incoming and outgoing correspondence, as well as an issue of the Greek-Canadian newspaper The Greek-Canadian Vēma, 337 (May 21, 1971) dedicated to the life and work of Kachtitsēs.
    - Kakridēs, Phanēs I., 1987-1992; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Kalokyrē, Liana, 1991-1995; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Kalphopoulos, Chrēstos, 1962; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Kaminēs, Stephanos, 1946; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Kaphtantzēs, Giōrgos, 1957-2003; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Includes incoming correspondence from Kaphtantzēs, a biographical statement, and two letters from his daughter to Tēlemachos Alaveras.
    - Karadēmou, Kōnstantina, 1993-1999; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Karamanlēs, Kōstas Al., 1995-2006; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Karantinos, Sōkratēs [Kratikon Theatron Voreiou Hellados], 1961-1976; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Karavias, Panos, 1977-1978; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Karellē, Zōe, 1955-1957; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Kargakos, Sarantos I., 2003-2006; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Karouzos, N. D., 1958; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Katapodēs, Nikos, 2002-2007; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Kazazēs, I. N., 2007; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Kentro Ereunas kai Meletēs tēs Neohellēnikēs Logotechnias kai tou Perivallontos-Instituto Alavera [Center for Research and Study of Modern Greek Literature and Environment- Alaveras Insitute], 2002; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Kentrou-Agathopoulou, Maria, 2002-2004; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Kephalas, Ēlias, 2004; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Konidarēs, Dēmētrēs, 1983-2005; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Korphēs, Tasos, 1956-1994; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Kotopoulē, Maria, 1999-2007; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Kotsiras, Giōrgēs, 1955-1994; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Kōtsopoulos, Thanos [Harma Thespidos], 1972-1979; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Kotzias, Alexandros, 1961-1992; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Kounelakēs, Dēmētrēs [Hē Larisa], 1970; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Kouphopoulos, Takēs, 1956-1957; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Koutlēs, Thanasēs, 1987-2002; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Krapsitēs, Vasilēs, 1961-1980; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Kratiko Theatro Voreiou Hellados, 1961-2006; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Kriaras, Emmanouēl, 1981-2006; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Krikos [A Greek Monthly Review), 1961; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Lampele, Phoula, 1973-1995; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Lamprellēs, Dēmētrēs N., 1981-2005; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Layton, Evro, 1970; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Lazăr, Elena, 2004-2005; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Liaskas, Vasilēs, 1955-1960; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Lignadēs, Tasos, 1964-1965; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - M (General), 1993-1999; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Includes correspondence from: Myrivēlēs, Stratēs; Manea, Norman; Melas, Spyros; Maurikios, Nikolas D.; Mertzos, Nikolaos; Mēliōnēs, Christophoros; Michalas, Tasos; Manganarēs, Apostolos; Mendrakos, T.; Michaēlidēs, Kōstas; Molyvidēs, Geōrgios; Mētropoulou, Kōstoula; Maphounēs, Thanasēs; Margarēs, Vasilēs; and Markakēs, Manōlēs.
    - Makrēs, Solōn, 1972-1995; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Malanos, Timos, 1956-1963; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Manousakēs, Giōrgēs, 1968-2004; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Mankliveras, Dionysēs K., 1978-2006; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Maphounēs, Athanasios, 1994; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Markoglou, Prodromos Ch., 1965-2007; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Markopoulos, Giōrgos, 1985-2006; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Mesevrinos, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Mastrodēmētrēs, P. D., 1972-1976; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Mauridēs, Panagiōtēs, 2004-2005; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 22)
      Includes photocopies of congratulation letters sent to Mauridēs from several Greek authors, friends, and acquaintances on his book: Mikres kai megales histories tēs katochēs stēn Kalamaria.
    - Meraklēs, Michalēs, 1960-2006; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Meralidou, Ph., 1980-1982; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Merkenidou, Helenē, 1978; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Mētras, Michalēs, 2005-2007; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Metron, 1991-2003; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Mētsakēs, Kariophilēs, 1969-2004; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Meskos, Markos, 1955-2005; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Miaritē, Zōē, 1987-1989; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Minotis, Alex, 1987-1988; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Modern Language Association of America, 1969-2006; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Morphes, 1952; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Mouchtarēs, Chrēstos N., 1959-1960; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Mourelos, Giōrgos I., 1962-1991; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mōysēs, Monachos, 1982-2006; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Music Society of Northern Greece, 1991; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - N (General), 1996-2005; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Includes incoming correspondence from Nikoretzos, Dēmētrēs and Nikolopoulos, Giannēs.
    - Nasioutzik, A. K., 1988; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Nea Poreia, 1956-2007; 2 folders (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
    - Niarchos, Thanasēs Th., 1965-1999; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Nikēphorou, Tolēs, 1982-1988; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Nomarchiakē Autodioikēsē Thessalonikēs (Prefecture of Thessalonikē), 1981-1998; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Organismos Politistikēs Prōteuousas tēs Eurōpēs (Thessalonikē, Greece), 1992-1997; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - P (General), 1963-2008; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Includes correspondecne from: Papanoutsos, E. P.; Papandreou, Nikos; Papadopoulos, Panagiōtēs and Eutychia; Papastamou, Olga; Pappas, Nikos; Papathanasopoulos, Thanasēs; Pelekanidēs, Stylianos M.; Phassou Kalpaxē, Giovanna; Plastēras, Kōnstantinos N.; Pieridēs, Giankos; Papasiōpēs, Leōnidas I.; Papasiōpēs, Paulos; Paraskeuopoulos, Panos; Palaiologos, Paulos; Phōtiadēs, Athanasios; Pallantios, Menelaos; Panagos, Giōrgos; and Plōritēs, Marios.
    - Palla, Maria, 2003-2005; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Panagiōtopoulos, Iōannēs Michaēl, 1955-1990; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Pantelia, Stylianē, 1991-2005; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Papakōnstantinou, Dēmētrēs K., 1969-1982; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Papakōnstantinou, Dēmētrēs, 1994-2002; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Papakōnstantinou, Michalēs, 1986-1997; 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Papantōnakēs, Geōrgios, 1991-1992; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Papathemelēs, Stelios, 1985; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Papatsōnēs, T. K. (Takēs Kōnstantinou), 1957-1967; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Papoutsopoulos, Nikos, 1995-2005; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Papp, Árpád, 1975; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Paraskeuopoulou, V. [Vassiliki] or Vazra, Persa, 1979-1991; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Paratērētēs, 1987-2004; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Paschalēs, Nicholas, 1976-1998; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Paschos, P. V., undated; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Paterakē, Giolanta, 1982-2007; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Pauleas, Sarantos, 1963-1969; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Pelitēs, Giannēs, 1995-2001; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Pentzikēs, Grēgorēs, 1998-2001; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Pentzikēs, Nikos Gavriēl, 1983-2004; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Pephanēs, Panagiōtēs, 1960-1963; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Peranthēs, Michalēs, 1955-1978; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Phestival Kinēmatographou Thessalonikēs [Thessalonikē Film Festival], 1969-1989; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 17)